Railroad Collection Photographs 6040 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Railroad Collection Photographs
1934-1968
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
6040 P
2.86 cubic feet
7.9 linear ft.
Photographs.
Largely western United States railroad prints and lantern slides. Lantern slides labeled as if for court exhibits.
5797421
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 08, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 29, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5003 P: U.S. President's Railroad Commission Photographs 5148 P: Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen Photographs 5149 P: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photographs 5182 P: Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen of America Photographs 5563 P: Railroad Photographs 6215 P: Neil P. Spiers Collection of U.S. Railroad Retirement Board Member Photographs 6268 P: Joint Committee of Adjustment for the Rock Island System's Order of Railway Conductors and Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photograph 6312 P: Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photographs 6312 PUBS: Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Publications 6321 P: Chairman Aubrey L. Miller Collection of A. T. & S. F. Railway General Grievance Committee Photographs
Railroads
5797421
- Order of Railway Conductors Home Association (1927) Photo Album (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  21 photographs
- Glass lantern slides (Box 1, Folder 2)
  7
- John Town Bridge 1890, one year after a flood (Box 1, Folder 3)
  1
- Labor News Conference (Box 1, Folder 4)
  28 photographs
- Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 1, Folder 5)
  26 photographs
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
  24 photographs
- ORC & B Photos. (1) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- ORC & B (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- ORC & B (3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  23 photographs
- Group photos (Box 1, Folder 10)
  6 photographs
- Misc. Photos (1) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  10 photographs
- Misc. photos (2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Group photos (Box 1, Folder 13)
  8 photographs
- Misc. Photos (Box 1, Folder 14)
  18 photographs
- Misc. Photos (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Misc. Photos (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Misc. photos (Box 1, Folder 17)
- A. F. Whitney (Box 1, Folder 18)
  1 photograph
- ORC & B photos (Box 1, Folder 19)
  3 photographs
- Misc. Photos (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Misc. Photos (Box 1, Folder 21)
  12 photographs
- Misc. Railroad photos (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ray Scott portrait photo (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photos of men in horse carriage (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Portrait photos, group photos, misc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  17 photographs
- Group photo (Box 2, Folder 5)
- American Red Cross, Railroad bridge (Box 2, Folder 6)
  2 photographs
- May 1946 photos (Box 2, Folder 7)
  7 photographs
- The Story of Ohio's Railroads (booklet); brittle photo of men in a horse carriage (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Various Railroad yards across the country (Box 2, Folder 9)
  13 photographs
- Railroad Officials (Box 2, Folder 10)
- H.E. Gilbert (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Elec. Draw. Atl. City -- 10/28/1906 (train accident) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Herb A. Stollard, James Janousek, Charles Thomas (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Group photos (Box 2, Folder 14)
  4 photographs
- Misc. Railroad Photos (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Misc. Photos - funeral, golfing, etc. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Unidentified group photograph (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Misc. Photos --- two booklets -- The Railroad Retirement Acts and Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act; The Hours of Service Act (Box 2, Folder 18)
  2
- Group shot of Railroad Officials (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Convention photographs (Box 2, Folder 20)
  5 photographs
- Photos of debris around Railway Stations, and photos of engines (Box 2, Folder 21)
  12
- ORC & B (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Yearbook of Railroad Facts (1967); 1966 Annual Report; news clipping; Why Railroad Featherbeds Must Go!; Signalman's Journal (1967) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Misc. Photos (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Unidentified group photo and photo of 2 men in a horse carriage (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Apr. ORCB; June Conductor; Memphis; Salt Lake City (Box 2, Folder 26)
  15
- Convention snapshots; Menu from Disneyland (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Photos of Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Father John J. Ryan (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Kate Shelley (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Unidentified group of men (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Negatives for Shelley Photos (Box 3, Folder 5)
- SUNA Convention May 20, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- G.H. Oram, General Secty. Treasurer ORCB-1948 - Negatives (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Honorable Jas. M. Mead (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Honorable Ralph F. Wagner (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Yermit, Ferguson, Farer, Benington (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Officers of SUNA (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Interior of Vestibule Cab (Box 3, Folder 12)
  2 photograph
- SUNA Office Building (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Port Jervis Lodge #1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- NYS Leg. Bd. BLFE (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Passengers of Railways (Box 3, Folder 16)
- W.J. Doble (Box 3, Folder 17)
- 1951 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Lane, Collins, Hampton (Box 3, Folder 19)
  14 photographs
- Engine Photos (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Railroad Construction Photos (Box 3, Folder 21)
- L.W. Williams (Box 3, Folder 22)
- James C. Mock, Signal Electrical Engineer at Michigan Central Railroad - 1937 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Frank M. Cassidy, Editor & manager Journal of the S.U.N.A., 1905 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Pictures of ORC Home - Lawanda, Georgia (Box 3, Folder 25)
  19 photographs
- Railroad Construction Photos (Box 3, Folder 26)
- ORCB Ceremony (Box 3, Folder 27)
  11 photographs
- Kate Shelley (cont.) (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Hostile Indians (Box 3, Folder 29)
- 1st Convention of Ladies Society, BLF&E (Box 3, Folder 30)
- BLF&E State leg. Board (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Negatives - Ladies Auxiliary of SUNA (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Legislative Board, B. of L.F. & E. State of New York, Jan. 1915 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Tom Ryan, Chairman BLF & E (Box 4, Folder 2)
- A- L.R. Anderson -- A-1--A22 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  26 slides
- A- L.R. Anderson -- A-22A--A-30 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  10 slides
- B-S.G. Vick -- B-1--B-24 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- B--S.G. Vick -- B-25--B-X1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  6 slides
- C--W.P. Dunn -- C-1--C-12 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- C--W.P. Dunn -- C-13--C-18 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- D--E.R. Guinea -- D-1--D-38 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- D--E.R. Guinea -- D-27--D-38 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  12 slides
- DR--E.R. Guinea Rebuttal -- DR-1--DR-4; E--H.G. Plock -- E-1--E-21 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- E--H.G. Plock -- E-22--E-28 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- E--H.G. Plock -- E-29--E-X12 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  17 slides
- F--E.J. Barley -- F-1--F-19 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  28 slides
- F--E.J. Barley -- F-20--F-40 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- F--E.J. Barley -- F-41--F-42C (Box 7, Folder 4)
  9 slides
- F--E.J. Barley -- F-43--F-53 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  11 slides
- G--J.B. Redmond -- G-1--G-15 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  15 slides
- H--J.W. Ritchie -- H-1--H-11 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- I--J.L. Golden -- I-1--I-4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- J--V.S. Zumwinkle -- J-1--J-22 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- J--V.S. Zumwinkle -- J-23--J-31 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- J--V.S. Zumwinkle -- J-31A--J-54 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- K--D.H. Anderson -- K-1--K-27 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  27 slides
- K--D.H. Anderson -- K-28--K-29; L-1--L-20 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  25 slides
- L-21--L-32 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- M--Mulhall, A.J. - Union Pacific -- M-1--M-13 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  13 slides
- N--Howell, Fred - Illinois Central -- N-1--N-25 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- N--Howell, Fred - Illinois Central -- N-26--N-41 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  14 slides
- O--Dubose -- O-1--O-16 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  16 slides
- O--Dubose -- O-17--O-33 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  8 slides
- P--Neupert -- P-1--P-26 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- P--Neupert -- P-26A--P-49 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  24 slides
- P--Neupert -- P-50--P-56 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- R--Vawter, H.M. Southern Pacific -- R-1--R-17 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Q--Vickers, S. - Southern Pacific -- Q-1--R-2C (Box 12, Folder 1)
- R-4--R-20 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- S--H. Pippy -- S-1--S-26 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- S--H. Pippy -- S-27--S-29 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  3 slides
- S-30--S-31 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  2 slides
- Various slides most are labeled individually; T - Technical - J.C. Hicks (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Various slides most are labeled individually (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Various slides most are labeled individually (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Various slides most are labeled individually (Box 14, Folder 1)
- U- Whitworth -- Southern RR -- U-i--U-26 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- U- Whitworth -- Southern RR -- U-27--U-51 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- V -- Larue, M.H. -- V-1--V-8 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- V -- Larue, M..H. -- V-9--V-35 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- V -- Larue, M.H. -- V-36--V-45 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- W-- Harp, A.A. -- W-1--W-9 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- X-- Shimmel and Various other slides (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Various slides, most are individually labeled (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Various slides, most individually labeled (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Various slides, most individually labeled (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Various slides, most individually labeled (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 20, Folder 3)
  26 slides -- ALCO-Turbocharger; ALCO-Engine Cooling
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 21, Folder 2)
  26 slides -- Axles-Gears & Bearings; Traction Motors
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 21, Folder 4)
  2 slides -- ALCO Locomotive Photos
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 22, Folder 2)
  26 slides -- Steam Heat Generators
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 22, Folder 3)
  26 slides -- EMD Locomotive Photos; EMD-Colored Drawings of Locomotives
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 23, Folder 1)
  26 slides -- EMD-Trucks; EMD-Axles-Gears-& Bearings; EMD-Traction Motors; EMD-Electrical
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Varied slides, not individually identified (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Unidentified open reel film (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Full tape of Milwaukee RR #1 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Unidentified open reel film (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Unidentified open reel film (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Unidentified open reel film (9/21/61 #1), 1961 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Bills, Chicago (Box 25, Folder 6)
- "C", RWM, good banana yard scenes (Box 25, Folder 7)
- RWM, "B" (mail bags, etc.) (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Unidentified photographs (Box 26, Folder 1)
  17 photos and maps
- Portraits (Box 26, Folder 2)
  3 photographs -- Sam Phillips; Carl Goff; Walter E. Jones
- Brotherhood Locomotive Firemen, Second Annual Convention; Washington Delegation, Denver 1916 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  3 photos
- Convention photographs (Box 26, Folder 4)
  7 photographs -- Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen of America, General Chairman's Meeting, March 18-19, 1960; General Chairman's Meeting, August 9-10, 1957; General Chairman's Meeting, August 15-16, 1953; Golden Anniv., August 18-22, 1952; General Chairman's Meeting, August 18-19, 1951; Testimonial Dinner in Honor of Mr. George N. Butler, Jan. 29, 1957; Convention of the Ladies Auxiliary to the Switchmen's Union of N.A., June 9-16, 1947
- Conference Railway Labor Executives, Conductors Division, Washington, D.C. March, 1934; James L. Karney photo; 33rd Conv. B. of R.T., Hollywood Fla. - Sept. 1968; Texas Del. B. of R.T., Hollywood, Fla. - Sept. 1968; 33rd Conv. B. of R.T., Hollywood (Box 27)
  - Panoramic photos -- Conference Railway Labor Executives, Conductors Division, Washington, D.C. March, 1934; 1 photo sorted from the 'misc. photos' box that had been stored above the mapcase; James L. Karney photo; 33rd Conv. B. of R.T., Hollywood Fla., 1934-1968 (Box 27, Folder 1)